Okay, hopefully you hopefully that was
helpful in understanding that there are
two types of variables. One that
actually holds the information and one
that tells you where that information is
actually being stored in memory. Um, so
I'm going to demonstrate this in a live
demo. Um, so over here I have a I have
well right here I'm bringing in
script.js and so when I go over here,
this is the code that's going to run
when I go over to the computer. I mean
over to the web browser. Tongue twisted
today. All right. So, I'm creating a
variable called a and I'm putting into
it a string. If you recall in our
example demonstration, um, our string is
being stored directly in a box in
memory. Um, so when I set B equal to A,
it goes into that variable, opens it up,
grabs the information out of it, and
copies it. So if B is storing um
so if A is storing the string hello, B
will now be storing the string hello. So
when we run this before we change A, we
should expect to see that both of them
are hello originally and then we're
going to change A and then we should see
that A is now high and B is hello.
So, let's go live.
And it says A was originally hello. B
was originally hello. A is now I. B is
now hello. And that makes sense because
what we did is we said set B equal to
whatever is inside of A. Where this
doesn't work is with an array. So if I
set one, two, and three in this array,
and then I said set B equal to A. If you
recall, when I create A, A is not
actually holding this array. It's
holding information about where that
array is actually sitting. So it's
telling me where I can go look for that
information. So when I copy B, what does
B copy? It doesn't copy the array. It
copies where the array is located. So
now if I change A at the zero position
to be high, B and A are both storing
information that says look next door for
the array. So now if I change the actual
array by using this syntax, then that
means that both B and A are pointing to
the exact same array. So let's go see
this live. Says A was originally 1 2 3.
B was originally 1 2 3. A is now high 2
three and B is now high 2 three. Why?
Because when we went out and we made a
copy of our variable A, all A was
holding was look next door. So now B is
holding the exact same information. So
when I go make a change to the actual
array, both of these are still telling
me that the actual array is next door,
which means they're both still pointing
to the exact same array.
And that is why you need to do something
called um spreading arrays or
copying arrays. Um, and I will show you
that in the next